Finding Aid for Lincoln Highway Association Records, 1911-1941
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
- Correspondence
  The Seiberling Section subseries (1916-1923) deals with portions of the route in Utah. Correspondence is arranged by association members: Austin Bement, Carl G. Fisher, Gael S. Hoag, Henry B. Joy, Henry C. Ostermann, Frank A. Seiberling, and miscellaneous authors. The section of the Highway is named after Frank A. Seiberling, who worked strenuously to solve the problems this section of the route presented.
  The Utah/Nevada suberies (1912-1927) covers discussion of the Highway throughout Utah and Nevada, especially dealing with problems of routing. Correspondents include Austin Bement, Carl G. Fisher, Gael S. Hoag, Henry B. Joy, Henry C. Ostermann, Arthur R. Pardington, Frank A. Seiberling, Secretary of Agriculture Henry C. Wallace, and miscellaneous authors.
  - Car Companies
    - September 6, 1912-November 29, 1912 (Box 2)
    - February 7, 1913-July 31, 1913 (Box 2)
    - August 4, 1913-September 9, 1913 (Box 2)
    - September 11, 1913-October 13, 1913 (Box 2)
    - October 14, 1913-November 20, 1913 (Box 2)
    - March 4, 1914-September 22, 1914 (Box 2)
    - October 14, 1914-March 20, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Subscriptions/Contributions
    - Blank forms (Box 2)
    - September 18, 1912-October 22, 1912 (Box 2)
    - October 24, 1912-February 4, 1913 (Box 2)
    - February 4, 1913-June 10, 1914 (Box 2)
    - March 1919 undated (Box 2)
  - Federal Government
    - September 24, 1912-May 4, 1923 (Box 2)
  - State Governments
    - September 13, 1913-July 20, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Auto Club of California
    - May 4, 1915-August 6, 1915 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - October 10, 1912-November 25, 1913 (Box 2)
    - December 19, 1913-November 25, 1925 (Box 2)
  - "Ideal" Section-Indiana
    - Bement, Austin
      - January 22, 1920-August 5, 1920 (Box 2)
      - September 10, 1920-January 3, 1923 (Box 2)
      - February 14, 1923-October 4, 1923 (Box 2)
      - November 19, 1923-September 9, 1925 (Box 2)
    - Ford, Edsel
      - March 11, 1924-September 3, 1925 (Box 2)
    - Jensen, Jens
      - May 3, 1922-May 25, 1928 (Box 2)
      - November 7, 1928-June 6, 1929 (Box 2)
    - Thompson, W.G. May 11, 1923-September 14, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Seiberling Section-Utah/Nevada
    - Bement, Austin
      - January 12, 1916-February 8, 1916 (Box 2)
      - February 9, 1916-June 23, 1916 (Box 2)
      - July 5, 1916-March 23, 1918 (Box 2)
      - March 27, 1918-May 10, 1918 (Box 2)
      - May 22, 1918-April 18, 1919 (Box 2)
      - April 24, 1919-July 10, 1919 (Box 2)
      - July 10, 1919-September 20, 1919 (Box 2)
      - January 23, 1919-April 15, 1926 (Box 2)
    - Fisher, Carl G.
      - February 8, 1916-January 12, 1918 (Box 2)
    - Hoag, Gael S.
      - April 5, 1916-May 30, 1920 (Box 2)
    - Joy, Henry B.
      - January 22, 1916-October 14, 1916 (Box 2)
      - October 16, 1916-November 27, 1916 (Box 2)
      - December 9, 1916-May 20, 1926 (Box 2)
    - Ostermann, Henry C.
      - December 3, 1915-February 21, 1918 (Box 2)
    - Seiberling, Frank A.
      - May 16, 1916-May 28, 1920 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous
      - March 19,1919-August 7, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Utah/Nevada
    - Bement, Austin
      - December 4, 1915-May 24, 1917 (Box 2)
      - July 2, 1917-October 7, 1918 (Box 2)
      - June 18, 1919-October 22, 1919 (Box 2)
      - October 23, 1919-February 12, 1923 (Box 2)
      - February 12, 1923 (Box 2)
      - March 28, 1923-June 2, 1924 (Box 2)
      - June 23, 1924-August 19, 1926 (Box 2)
      - August 26, 1926-September 19, 1927 (Box 2)
    - Fisher, Carl G.
      - August 11, 1913-September 11, 1919 (Box 2)
    - Hoag, Gael S.
      - August 15, 1912-January 12, 1916 (Box 2)
      - January 25, 1916-March 6, 1916 (Box 2)
      - May 1, 1916-April 23, 1920 (Box 2)
      - February 12, 1922-April 24, 1923 (Box 2)
      - September 15, 1925-October 26, 1927 (Box 2)
    - Joy, Henry B.
      - May 26, 1914-July 16, 1920 (Box 2)
      - July 20, 1920 (Box 2)
      - July 20, 1920-Februrary 10, 1923 (Box 2)
      - December 21, 1923-November 19, 1924 (Box 2)
      - May 4, 1926-October 13, 1927 (Box 2)
    - Ostermann, Henry C.
      - February 23, 1915-October 7, 1919 (Box 2)
    - Pardington, Arthur R.
      - August 22, 1913-March 27, 1915 (Box 2)
    - Seiberling, Frank A.
      - October 5, 1918-February 10, 1921 (Box 2)
    - Wallace, Henry C.
      - 1922-June 6, 1923 (Box 2)
      - June 7, 1923-June 18, 1923 (Box 2)
      - June 28, 1923-December 21, 1923 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous
      - September 13, 1913-February 7, 1920 (Box 2)
      - February 21, 1920-January 4, 1922 (Box 2)
      - March 13, 1923-August 27, 1924 (Box 2)
      - Letter book & Blueprints, 1920-1921 (Box 2)
- Planning
  The Planning series (1914-1940) covers details relating to planning the route of the Lincoln Highway. The series is divided into the subseries Documents Relating to Utah, 1921-1924, Routing, and Markers.
  Documents Relating to Utah, 1921-1924 is a collection of a variety of records. Originally housed in a grey binder the contents include correspondence, editorials, reports, and press releases regarding the Lincoln Highway in Utah. The first document is an index covering all of the documents in this section. The index was created when the binder was assembled, presumably by an Association member.
  Routing (1914-1930) includes correspondence covering the route through Ohio, Wyoming, Utah, Nevada, and California. Penciled routes, proposed mileages, and road log books all shed light on the detailed routing process. Other information regarding the route including rail roads and campsites is also present.
  Markers (1925-1940) includes correspondence, notes, and sketches regarding the construction and placement of markers along the entire route of the Lincoln Highway. In addition, an original "Log of 1928 Markers" lists the locations of all the markers along the Highway. The original 3,000 markers were placed by the Boy Scouts of America.
  - Documents Relating to Utah, 1921-1924
    - Binder, Small (Box 5)
    - October 26, 1921-November 9, 1921 (Box 2)
    - January 26, 1922-February 2, 1922 (Box 2)
    - February 27, 1922-January 26, 1923 (Box 2)
    - September 16, 1922-December 1922 (Box 2)
    - December 15, 1922-February 12, 1923 (Box 2)
    - March 28, 1923-May 24, 1923 (Box 2)
    - April 16, 1923-September 26, 1923 (Box 2)
    - July 6, 1923-January 18, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Routing
    - Correspondence
      - Ohio
        - January 22, 1914-January 31, 1916 (Box 3)
        - February 11, 1916-June 13, 1921 (Box 3)
        - June 14, 1921-June 25, 1921 (Box 3)
        - June 25, 1921-March 14, 1930 (Box 3)
      - Wyoming
        - May 7, 1914-December 21, 1918 (Box 3)
      - Utah, Nevada, California
        - February 22, 1917-July 7, 1919 (Box 3)
    - Mileages
      - Penciled Routes
        - Utah, Nevada, California, 6 Folders (Box 3)
      - Proposed Mileages
        - Utah, Nevada, California, 5 folders (Box 3)
      - Log Books
        - 1921 1923 1926 (Box 3)
        - 1920 undated (Box 3)
        - 1918 1930 undated (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Blueprint of Routes, Wyoming, Utah, Nevada (Box 3)
      - Rail Road Crossing Information, 1927, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Campsite and Filling Station, "Ideal" Section (Box 3)
  - Markers
    - Notes & Correspondence
      - June 1, 1925-February 8, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence
      - February 10, 1934-January 1940 (Box 3)
    - Notes & Sketches
      - undated (Box 3)
    - Log of 1928 Markers (Box 3)
    - Photocopy of 1928 Log
      - Cover-Pennsylvania 10 (Box 3)
      - Pennsylvania 11-West Virginia (Box 3)
      - Ohio-Ohio 19 (Box 3)
      - Ohio 20-Illinois 4 (Box 3)
      - Illinois 5-Iowa 4 (Box 3)
      - Iowa 5-Iowa 25 (Box 3)
      - Iowa 26-Nebraska 3 (Box 3)
      - Nebraska 4-Nebraska 23 (Box 3)
      - Nebraska 24-Wyoming 2 (Box 3)
      - Wyoming 3-Utah 5 (Box 3)
      - Nevada-California 10 (Box 3)
      - California 11-California 22 (Box 3)
- Publicity
  The Publicity series (1911-1993) includes materials devoted to promoting the construction and use of the Lincoln Highway as well as celebrating the Highway's achievements. The series is divided into subseries including Speeches and Essays, Published Articles, Newspaper Clippings, Editorials, Press Releases, and Press Sheets.
  Speeches and Essays (1913-1924) covers a variety of topics relating to the Lincoln Highway. Board members of the Association authored the majority of essays in the collection. Typical speeches and essays focused on the extreme need for the Lincoln Highway as well as the benefits the Highway would provide.
  Published Articles (1918-1992) contains original articles written about the Lincoln Highway. These include articles written by board members in promotion of the Lincoln Highway as well as scholars and enthusiasts celebrating the Lincoln Highway's achievements.
  Newspaper Clippings (1911-1926) are original articles published about the Lincoln Highway. The majority of clippings come from local and regional newspapers. Clippings regarding California and Utah are the most plentiful in the collection.
  The Editorials subseries (1916-1926) contains editorials about the Lincoln Highway. Two folders discuss the Highway in general as well as various places along the route. There is a sub section devoted specifically to the "Ideal" Section in Indiana (1915-1922). This section seems to have been artificially created at a later date. The editorials come from a variety of sources, but are all typed in the same format and style. Two folders cover correspondence regarding editorials.
  The Press Releases and Press Sheets subseries (1917-1924) contain official statements and updates by the Association from Detroit, Michigan. The subsections "Ideal" Section and Utah contain releases specifically focused on the development of the Lincoln Highway in these areas.
  - Speeches and Essays
    - September 1913 undated (Box 3)
    - 1915-1917 (Box 3)
    - April 4, 1917April 26, 1917 (Box 3)
    - March 1923-March 5, 1924 (Box 3)
    - Undated, "Ideal" Section (Box 3)
  - Published Articles
    - 1918-1993 (Box 3)
    - Iowan, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Smithsonian, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Highway Days, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - May 16, 1911-October 15, 1916 (Box 3)
    - California
      - November 5, 1916-December 1921 (Box 3)
    - Utah
      - August 31, 1915-October 22, 1916 (Box 3)
      - June 17, 1923-December 1, 1926 undated (Box 3)
  - Editorials
    - November 21, 1916-October 1926 undated (Box 3)
    - March 19, 1923-June 3, 1923 undated (Box 3)
    - "Ideal" Section
      - July 8, 1915-August 14, 1922 (Box 3)
      - August 14, 1922-August 27, 1922 (Box 3)
      - August 27, 1922-October 1922 (Box 3)
      - October 1, 1922-October 15, 1922 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence
      - November 16, 1916-January 3, 1917 (Box 3)
      - June 7, 1923-December 7, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Press Releases
    - April 18, 1917 undated (Box 3)
    - "Ideal" Section
      - August 1921-October 4, 1922 (Box 3)
      - December 11, 1922-June 1, 1923 (Box 3)
      - June 15, 1923-January 28, 1924 (Box 3)
      - Undated (Box 3)
    - Utah
      - Binder, Large (Box 3)
      - October 25, 1920 (Box 3)
      - January 22, 1922 (Box 3)
      - April 17, 1922-October 24, 1922 (Box 3)
      - February 3, 1923 (Box 3)
      - March 3, 1923-May 28, 1923 (Box 3)
      - June 13, 1923-March 24, 1924 (Box 3)
  - Press Sheets
    - Scrapbook of "Lincoln Highway Press Sheets, starting with last issue September 1918" (Vol. V No. 38 to Vol. VI No. 3), with loose "Special" bulletins laid-in after last pasted-in press sheets (Port Port. 1)
- Publications
  The Publications series (1915-1935) covers materials published by the Association as well as materials about the Lincoln Highway. The main subseries are Newspapers, Road Guides, and Maps.
  A scrapbook contains articles and incoming correspondence to Gael S. Hoag and Frank A. Seiberling regarding the book, The Lincoln Highway: The Story of a Crusade that Made Transportation History, published by the Association in 1935. The majority of letters came from supporters requesting copies of the book and praising its success including: officials from the Department of Agriculture, Roads, Public Works and other governmental bodies, libraries and universities, industry, engineers, and auto clubs. Letters and clippings are not in chronological order and cover the period 1935-1939.
  The Newspapers subseries (1915-1926) includes runs of The Lincoln Highway (1915-1919) and the Lincoln Highway Forum (1918-1926).
  Road Guides contains printed local guides for portions of the route running through Colorado, Wyoming, Utah, Nevada, and California. The second, third, and fourth editions of The Complete Official Road Guide of the Lincoln Highway are included. These volumes are particularly special as they were the personal copies of Association board members Henry C. Ostermann (2nd edition) and Gael S. Hoag (3rd and 4th editions). All three copies include hand written notes throughout the guides by their owners.
  The Maps subseries (1905-1935) contains maps covering geography and roads on the national, regional, state, and local scale. National maps cover the national highway systems. Regional maps include national and state roads for more than one state. State maps include California, Colorado, Nevada, and Utah. Several maps depict the paved and dirt roads throughout several national parks. All maps are listed individually within their category and dates are provided when available.
  Route maps along the Lincoln Highway provide mileages for specific sections of the highway and usually come in small strips. There is a complete route map set published by the Lincoln Highway Association detailed the drive from New York to San Francisco. Another important contribution to the route maps section includes maps published by the Automobile Club of Southern California. These route maps cover portions of the Lincoln Highway as well as other regional routes such as the Midland Trail and the Coast Route.
  - Correspondence Scrapbook, 1935-1939 (Box 5)
  - Newspapers
    - The Lincoln Highway
      - October 6, 1915-December 8, 1915 (Box 4)
      - December 15, 1915-Februrary 23, 1916 (Box 4)
      - March 1, 1916-April 26, 1916 (Box 4)
      - May 3, 1916-June 28, 1916 (Box 4)
      - July 12, 1916-August 30, 1916 (Box 4)
      - September 6, 1916-October 18, 1916 (Box 4)
      - November 1, 1916-December 20, 1916 March 1917 March 1919 (Box 4)
    - Lincoln Highway Forum
      - May 1918-August 15, 1919 (Box 4)
      - September 1, 1919-Februrary 15, 1920 (Box 4)
      - March 15, 1920-December 15, 1920 (Box 4)
      - February 1921-October 1921 (Box 4)
      - November 1921-December 1922 (Box 4)
      - May 1923-November 1923 (Box 4)
      - January 1924-March 1925 (Box 4)
      - April 1925-February 1926 (Box 4)
      - March 1926-December 1926 (Box 4)
  - Road Guides
    - Printed Guides
      - Colorado, Wyoming (Box 4)
    - Printed Guides
      - Utah, Nevada, California, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Printed Mileages
      - Utah, Nevada, California, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - The Complete Official Road Guide of the Lincoln Highway. The Lincoln Highway Association. National Headquarters, Detroit, Michigan.
      - H.C. Ostermann's Second Edition, 1916 (Box 5)
      - Gael S. Hoag's Third Edition, 1918 (Box 5)
      - Gael S. Hoag's Fourth Edition, 1921 (Box 5)
  - Maps
    - National Maps
      - National Maps Envelope, 1935 (Box 4)
      - Pikes Peak Ocean-To-Ocean Highway, 1915 (Box 4)
      - United States System of Highways
        - November 11, 1926 Corrected to July 15, 1930 color (Box 4)
        - November 11, 1926 Corrected to July 1, 1935 color (Box 4)
    - Regional Maps, 2 folders
      - The Pasear, Inyo Good Road Club, ca. 1915 (Box 4)
      - Mountains to Coast Road Map, Lincoln Highway Garage Company of Ely, Nevada, 1918 (Box 4)
      - Western Pacific Railroad, Feather River Route through California, Nevada, Utah, Corrected to June 1, 1921 (Box 4)
      - Utah Map Showing State Road System, State Road Commission, 1922 together with: (Box 4)
      - Road Map of the State of Nevada, Department of Highways, undated, color (Box 4)
      - Map of Strategic Routes Between Salt Lake City, Utah and California, Lincoln Highway Association, undated, 2 copies in color, 1 copy in black and white (Box 4)
      - Utah and Nevada Regional Lincoln Highway Map, Proposed by Salt Lake, undated (2 copies) (Box 4)
    - State Maps, 4 folders
      - City Map of Los Angeles, 1905 (Box 4)
      - Main Roads in Colorado, State Highway Commission of Colorado, December 1911 (Box 4)
      - Security Automobile Road Map of San Diego County, 1911 (Box 4)
      - Security Automobile Road Map of Los Angeles and Adjacent Counties, 1912 (Box 4)
      - Utah, Maps of State Roads, State Road Commission, 1915-1916 color (annotated) (Box 4)
      - Southeastern California, The Federal Aid Highway System Progress Map, Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Public Roads, November 9, 1921 Corrected to August 31, 1935 (Box 4)
      - Southwestern California, The Federal Aid Highway System Progress Map, Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Public Roads, November 9, 1921 Corrected to August 31, 1935 (Box 4)
      - Central California, The Federal Aid Highway System Progress Map, Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Public Roads, November 9, 1921 Corrected to September 1, 1936 (Box 4)
      - Northern California, The Federal Aid Highway System Progress Map, Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Public Roads, November 9, 1921 Corrected to December 1, 1936 (Box 4)
      - Utah Map Showing State Road System, State Road Commission, 1922 (annotated) (Box 4)
      - Utah, Types of Surfacing on Sate Road System, November 1, 1922 (Box 4)
      - Utah Map Showing State Road System, State Road Commission, 1923 (2 copies) (Box 4)
      - Map Showing Construction Progress, State Highway System of Nevada, December 8, 1923 (Box 4)
      - State Road Map of Utah, State Road Commission, 1926 color (2 copies) (Box 4)
      - Partial Nevada State Road Map, undated, color (Box 4)
      - Hotel Plaza, San Francisco, undated, color (Box 4)
    - National Park Maps
      - Eldorado National Forest, California, Mt. Diablo Meridian, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, 1916 (Box 4)
      - Automobile Guide Map Showing Roads in the Yosemite National Park, California, Department of the Interior, National Park Service, March 1, 1916 (Box 4)
      - Automobile Guide Map Showing Roads in the Glacier National Park, Montana, Department of the Interior, National Park Service, 1917 (Box 4)
      - Automobile Guide Map Showing Roads in the Mount Rainier National Park, Washington, Department of the Interior, National Park Service, 1917 (Box 4)
      - Map Showing All Routes into Yosemite National Park, California State Automobile Association, undated, color (Box 4)
    - Route Maps
      - National Route Maps, Lincoln Highway Association, 3 folders
        - General Map of Transcontinental Routes with Principal Connections, American Automobile Association, 1912-1913 (annotated) (Box 4)
        - Map of the Midland Trail Showing Every City, Town, Village, and Hamlet Throughout Its Entire Length, Midland Trail Association, October 1915 color (Box 4)
        - The Lincoln Highway, Lincoln Highway Association, 1924March 1, 1928 color (Box 4)
        - Lincoln Highway, New York to San Francisco, 17 Maps, Lincoln Highway Association, undated (Box 4)
        - Lincoln Highway, New York to San Francisco, 17 Maps, Lincoln Highway Association, undated (16 Maps present-annotated) (Box 4)
      - Regional Route Maps, 2 folders
        - Stockton to Sacramento, Route and Map Bureau, California State Automobile Association, undated (Box 4)
        - Los Angeles to Witter and Santa Ana, undated (Box 4)
        - Main Roads Between San Francisco-Lake Tahoe and Reno, Nevada, undated (Box 4)
        - Portion of Great Salt Lake, Utah, undated (Box 4)
        - Automobile Route East of the Sierras from Los Angeles to Lake Tahoe, Touring Bureau, Route and Map Service, Automobile Club of Southern California, Part One and Two, 1912 (Box 4)
        - Sacramento to Silver Fork and Sacramento to Auburn, Route and Map Bureau, California State Automobile Association, February 10, 1915 (Box 4)
        - Automobile Roads from San Francisco to Sacramento via Sacramento Causeway, Route and Map Bureau, California State Automobile Association, undated (Box 4)
        - San Francisco to Stockton, Route and Map Bureau, California State Automobile Association, undated (Box 4)
        - Automobile Roads from San Francisco to Sacramento via Martinez, Cordelia & Davis also via Sausalito, Black Point, Napa & Cordelia, California State Automobile Association, undated (annotated) (Box 4)
        - Automobile Roads of San Francisco Contra Costa and Alameda Counties, Touring Bureau, California State Automobile Association, undated (annotated) (Box 4)
        - Omaha to Chicago and Philadelphia, Touring Bureau, Route and Map Service, Automobile Club of Southern California, undated (Box 4)
        - Official Lincoln Highway Guide Thru Iowa, Midland Map & Engineering Company, 1820 (Box 4)
        - Ely to Salt Lake City, Touring Bureau, Route and Map Service, Automobile Club of Southern California, 1917 (Box 4)
        - Stockton to Sacramento, Route and Map Service, Automobile Club of Southern California, February 10, 1915 (Box 4)
        - Silver Fork, California to Reno, Nevada and Truckee, California to Reno, Nevada, Route and Map Service, Automobile Club of Southern California, February 10, 1915 (Box 4)
        - Auburn to Truckee, Route and Map Service, Automobile Club of Southern California, February 7, 1915 (Box 4)
      - Automobile Club of Southern California
        - Sacramento to Salt Lake City Case, undated (Box 4)
        - Sacramento to Lake Tahoe & Reno via Placerville, undated (Box 4)
        - Reno to Ely, 1918 (Box 4)
        - Ely to Salt Lake City, 1917 undated, 2 folders (Box 4)
        - Salt Lake City to New York Case, undated (Box 4)
        - Salt Lake City to Omaha, 1919 undated, 5 folders (Box 4)
        - Omaha to Chicago & Philadelphia, undated, 3 folders (Box 4)
        - Philadelphia to New York, undated (Box 4)
        - Miscellaneous Maps Case, undated (Box 4)
        - Los Angeles to Ely via the Midland Trail, undated, 3 folders (Box 4)
        - Sacramento & Lake Tahoe via Truckee, undated (Box 4)
        - Los Angeles to San Francisco via the Coast Route, 1917-1918undated (Box 4)
        - Miscellaneous Routes, 1918 undated, 3 folders (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series is comprised of scrapbooks, photographs, stationery, and correspondence between the Lincoln Highway Association and the University of Michigan. The series' correspondence deals with the transfer of records to the Transportation Library, Engineering Department, lending of photographs, and the transactions between the library and Walt Disney Productions regarding several reels of film about the Lincoln Highway. Photographs include shots of the highway previously published as well as original photos of several board members. Photographs from the collection have been digitized and are accessible online at the Lincoln Highway Digital Image Collection. The Lincoln Highway Digital Image Collection contains over 3,000 images including views of construction underway, towns and cities, markers, bridges, cars, camp sites, scenic views, and snapshots of Association directors and field secretaries traveling the route.
  - Photographs
    - On the Road (Box 4)
    - Directors, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Stationery (Box 4)